hartfordlife.com 2018-12-29

# Online Privacy Policy | The Hartford

_Last Updated June 20, 2018_

The Hartford values your trust and is committed to the responsible management, use and protection of personal information. This Online Privacy Policy is applicable to the information collected by, from or about you during your use of our website (https://www.thehartford.com, the **“Website”** ) and its affiliate sites, our mobile applications, and any other online connected tools. We will refer to these websites and online connected tools collectively as the **“Services”** or the **“Hartford Services”** throughout this Online Privacy Policy.

This Online Privacy Policy supplements, but does not replace other applicable policies, practices and privacy notices that may relate to specific business relationships you have with The Hartford or to certain products or services, as described in the applicable privacy notice. At the start of our business relationship with you as a client, we will give you a copy of our privacy notice that applies to that relationship, if applicable. In the event of a conflict between this Online Privacy Policy and a privacy notice for a specific product or service, the specific product or service privacy notice shall govern.

##  Quick Links

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use Information
  * How We Share Information
  * Links to Other Online Services
  * Children's Privacy
  * Social Media
  * How We Protect Information
  * International Users
  * Cookies and Similar Technologies
  * Your Choices
  * Changes to This Policy
  * Contact

###  INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We collect various types of information provided by users of the Services. This may include such information as:

  * **Contact and Identifying Information:** We may collect contact and identifying information, such as names, home addresses, email addresses, phone numbers, dates of birth, and in some instances Social Security numbers or health information, and other application or quote information.
  * **Application, Quote, or Claim:** If you submit an application, quote, or a claim, we may collect information that you provide and other related information such as automobile information (including driver’s license number and VIN).
  * **Account Information:** If you create, register, or connect an online account in connection with our Services, we may store your username, password (and password hint information) and other basic account information that you may provide or that may be associated with that account.
  * **Job Application:** If you apply for a job with us, we may collect information about your work and educational history, and other information that you choose to provide us in connection with your application.
  * **Automatically Collected Information:** We and third party online advertising and analytics companies may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to automatically collect information about your online activity, browser and device as well as to collect information when you interact with the Services or other The Hartford offerings. In addition to the information above collected generally by the Services, unique device IDs, mobile phone numbers, geo-location data, or call logs may be collected through our mobile applications. See the “Cookies” and “Your Choices” section below for more information on these technologies and your choices.
  * **Log Information:** We also collect log information when you use the Services, which may include, information about how you have used the services, device information, access times, IP addresses, and related browsing information.

We and third party online advertising and analytics companies may collect personal information relating to users of our Services over time and across different websites.

###  HOW WE USE INFORMATION

We use information provided by individuals who use our Services to fulfill the purpose for which the user provided the information and for other purposes as permitted by law, such as:

  * Providing you with the Services that you request, such as by completing transactions, processing claims, or providing a quote for one of our products
  * Communicating with you, for example to respond to inquiries
  * Providing you with information, including communications and interest based advertisements on the Website and other websites you visit and marketing communications
  * Informing you of job opportunities and evaluating your suitability for a job
  * Completing a survey
  * Developing operating, delivering, maintaining, improving, enhancing, and protecting the Website and other Services we provide
  * Monitoring, analysis, and research, including of trends, and usage, and advertising-related services
  * Enhancing the safety and security of the Services and preventing fraud or protecting our or our customers’ rights or property
  * Enforcing applicable terms and conditions and other applicable policies
  * Other purposes specifically disclosed at the time the information is requested

We may de-identify information collected by removing identifiers, such as your name, or by aggregating information about multiple users. We may work with third parties to aggregate such information on our behalf. Aggregate information collected on the Services does not personally identify you, and we may use aggregated information for the purposes described above, and share aggregate information with third parties for lawful purposes.

We also may combine information collected through the Services with other information about you.

###  HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION

####  Disclosures Among our Affiliates

If we share your information among our affiliates for marketing purposes, in certain circumstances as required by applicable laws, we will inform you and provide you with an opt-out option, and upon request, we will provide to you a list of all third parties with whom personal information has been shared.

####  Disclosures to Third Parties

We work with third parties that provide services to us and partner with third parties to develop, operate, deliver, maintain, improve, enhance, and protect the Services and in connection with other The Hartford offerings and operations. We may share your information with such third parties. Those parties can include but are not limited to:

  * Financial service providers, such as independent agents, brokerage firms, insurance companies
  * Website hosting or information technology consulting service providers
  * Marketing and promotion service providers
  * Data analysis service providers
  * Legal service providers
  * Accounting service providers
  * Administrative service providers
  * Security service providers
  * Application service providers

We may also share information about users and customers with nonaffiliated companies with whom we have a marketing or other business relationship, including nonaffiliated financial services providers with whom we jointly market products.

####  Other Disclosures

We may also disclose your information to:

  1. Comply with applicable laws
  2. Respond to governmental inquires or requests
  3. Comply with valid legal processes
  4. Protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of https://www.thehartford.com visitors, users of the Services, customers and the public
  5. Permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain
  6. Enforce our Terms of Service

In the event there is a change or contemplated change in the corporate structure of The Hartford, such as a merger, consolidation, sale, liquidation or transfer of substantial assets, The Hartford may disclose your information and may, in its sole discretion, transfer, sell or assign information collected on and through the Services, including your information, to one or more affiliated or nonaffiliated third parties.

###  LINKS TO OTHER ONLINE SERVICES

The Services may contain links to other online services. The operators of those other online services may collect information about you, including through cookies or other technologies. If you click on a link to an external online service, you will leave The Hartford Services and this Online Privacy Policy will not apply to your use of and activity on those other online services.

If you provide information through any other online services, your transaction will occur on that online service (not The Hartford Services) and the information you provide will be collected by, and controlled by, the privacy policy of the operator of that online service. Links on the Services to other online services are provided only as a convenience, and the inclusion of such links does not imply endorsement of the linked content. We encourage you to read the legal notice posted on those online services, including their privacy policies. We have no responsibility or liability for your access or use of, and the data collection and use practices of, other online services.

###  CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

The Hartford's Services are not directed to or intended for children. The Hartford does not knowingly collect or post information from children under the age of 13, in compliance with laws protecting the privacy of children. You can visit the Federal Trade Commission’s [website](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/privacy-and-security/children%27s-privacy) to learn more about the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

###  SOCIAL MEDIA

The Hartford maintains profiles and/or pages on various social media sites including Facebook and Twitter. If you choose to “Like” The Hartford on Facebook, “Follow” The Hartford on Twitter, or take any similar action on another social media site, you are providing your consent to receive information updates, including solicitations, from The Hartford. To stop receiving this information from The Hartford on a social media site, you must follow the procedure established by the social media site. For example, on Facebook, you must click “Unlike” on The Hartford’s page, and, on Twitter, you must click “Unfollow” on The Hartford’s profile.

###  HOW WE PROTECT INFORMATION

The protection and security of your information is important to us. We work to adopt reasonable physical, administrative, and technical safeguards to protect the personal information transmitted between users and the Services and the personal information stored on our servers, and we require third parties with whom we share personal information to use reasonable precautions to safeguard such information. Unfortunately, no method of transmitting or storing data can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, although we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us through, or in connection with, the Services. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), you must immediately notify us by contacting us at the contact information listed below. In the event that we believe the security of your personal information in our possession or control may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. If notification is appropriate, we would endeavor to do so as promptly as possible under the circumstances, and, to the extent we have your email address, we may notify you by email.

Security tip: If you receive an email or other correspondence requesting that you provide any sensitive information (including your password or social security number) via email or to a website that does not seem to be affiliated with the Services, or that otherwise seems suspicious to you, please do not provide such information. Report such requests to us at the contact information listed below.

###  INTERNATIONAL USERS

This Online Privacy Policy applies to our United States operations. We maintain the Services in the United States, and the Services are not intended to subject The Hartford or any affiliated entity to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. The Hartford does not represent or warrant that the Services, or any part thereof, are appropriate or available for use in any particular jurisdiction. Those who choose to access the Services, do so on their own initiative and at their own risk. Regardless of where you are located, by using the Services you consent to the transfer and processing of your information to and in the United States, which may not provide the same level of protection for your personal information as your home country. You are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules and regulations when you use our Services.

###  COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES

We or third party online advertising and analytics companies may use tools and services to gather, analyze, and store information about users, including for statistical purposes, reporting, attribution, analytics, market research, interest based advertising, ad delivery and other purposes described in this Privacy Policy. These third parties use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to help analyze how You use online services. Generally speaking, cookies are small text files that are placed on your browser that can be used to identify you across web pages and sessions. Web beacons are small pieces of code that can communicate information about your device or browser to a server. For example, we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Please use the following link to understand how Google Analytics collects and processes data: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>.

###  YOUR CHOICES

You may be able to set your browser to reject cookies. Please review your browser or device’s “Help” file to learn the best way to modify your settings. Please note that rejecting cookies may disrupt certain functionality of the Website. You may also be able to opt out of online interest based advertising from certain third parties that participate in the opt-out, information is available at [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/). In addition, please note that The Hartford does not currently respond to web browser “do not track” signals or other mechanisms that provide you control over information collected over time and across different web sites following your visit to one of our Services. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Online Privacy Policy. See [https://allaboutdnt.com](https://allaboutdnt.com/) for more information on this topic.

If your contact information changes, if you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us or to have us share your information with third parties for marketing purposes, or if you wish to inquire about the information we have collected about you, please submit a request at the contact information listed below.

###  CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We reserve the right to amend this Online Privacy Policy at any time in order to address future developments of The Hartford, the Services, or changes in industry or legal trends. We will post the revised Online Privacy Policy on this page. You can determine when the Online Privacy Policy was revised by referring to the “Last Updated” legend on the top of this page. Any changes will become effective upon the posting of the revised Online Privacy Policy on the Website. By continuing to use the Services following such changes, you will be deemed to have agreed to such changes. If you do not agree with the terms of this Online Privacy Policy, in whole or part, you can choose to not continue to use the Services.

###  CONTACT

If you have any questions or comments about this Online Privacy Policy, or our use of your information collected through the Services, please contact us at The Hartford - Privacy Law, One Hartford Plaza, Hartford, CT 06155, or alternatively, [CorporatePrivacyOffice@thehartford.com](mailto:CorporatePrivacyOffice@thehartford.com).
